I had an eraser
这我高中的时候
like this in high school.
也用这样的橡皮
Ji Yuheng likes
纪昱恒也喜欢
this type too?
这样的
That's so cute!
也太可爱了吧
Maybe it belonged to his "ex".
说不定也是白月光的
You have a sore muscle?
酸疼
Kind of.
有一点
I'll give you a massage.
我给你按按
It hurts here.
这儿还挺疼
In my experience, massage works
以我的经验啊
when pain is felt.
疼才有效果
Really?
真的
What's your plan for tomorrow?
你明天有什么安排呀
I haven't decided yet.
暂时还没定呢
If you are free
你没什么安排
tomorrow,
正好
I have a favor to ask.
我有事想求你
What is it?
你说
I'm meeting a client tomorrow.
明天我要去见一个客户
Can you go with me?
你陪我一起去行不行
I feel confident
有你在
and will definitely make it
我心里踏实
when you're around.
肯定能谈成
Isn't it inappropriate?
不太合适吧
What's so inappropriate?
有什么不合适的
You're my husband.
你是我老公
Please, Mr. Ji.
求求你啦纪总
Help me out.
帮帮我嘛
Alright.
好
Is that a yes?
答应啦
Here.
来
Check it.
先看这个
Longhu Glass?
龙虎玻璃
I prefer
我这个人呢
to stay
做人做事
on the safe side.
讲究的就是一个稳妥
Because we've
因为我俩呀
been through hard times.
都是从苦日子过来的
We think money
所以对钱这个东西呢
is uneasy to earn.
就觉得来之不易
[Yes.]
是
[We're trying to grow our company.]
我们是想把公司做大
[There are many banks that want to invest]
也有好多家银行找我们
[in our company.]
想投
But I turned them down.
被我一一拒绝了
I always feel that money
我总觉得这个
borrowed from the bank
从银行借的钱
is not my own.
它终归不是自己的
[I'll have to pay it back with interest.]
还得加价还
[It's not a good deal.]
不划算
So I don't think your
所以说你们这个事啊
proposal is safe enough.
我觉得还是不稳妥
[On this point,]
在这一点上呢
we both have the
我们兄弟二人的想法
same opinion.
是一样的
When Xiaoning reached me,
之前小涂联系我
I thought,
我呢
because we're from
也是看在这
the same hometown,
咱们都是老乡的份上
and it's not easy
你们这
for you guys in marketing,
搞营销也不容易
I was thinking to
风吹日晒的
have a nice chat
想着叫你们过来
together.
这聊聊见见无所谓
But we haven't
不过这贷款
considered a loan seriously.
我们还真没考虑过
I know
我明白
what you mean.
二位柳总的意思
And I certainly won't force you
当然也不会
to take out a loan.
逼着二位贷款
It's an honor to
今天非常荣幸
meet you both today.
可以认识二位
Feel free to call me
以后有任何
for any future
关于银行的需求
banking needs.
都可以随时找我
[Okay.]
好
By the way, can you recommend
对你们现在银行
good financial products from your bank?
有没有好的理财产品呢
We can consider.
这个我们可以考虑考虑
Sure.
当然有了
We will do an evaluation based on
而且我们会根据您的
your pre-invested capital
预投资金
and business operations,
和企业经营情况
and customize
做一个评估
a financial product
定制一个
that works best for you.
最适合您的理财产品
You have customization services?
还可以定制
This might work.
这个听着行
[Please let us know]
那你看
[what we need to do]
具体需要怎么操作
[and what we]
我们这边需要
[need to prepare.]
准备什么材料
I'll
等
see you
我这一轮
after
展销会结束呢
the fair.
咱们再碰一碰
The wealth management department
这个会由我们行里
of our bank is
专门负责理财的部门
at your service for it.
进行对接
But, don't worry.
不过您二位可以放心
Xiaoning is also good at
小涂对于理财业务
the financial management business.
也很熟悉
She'll be there.
她会全程进行配合
Does it
那
go to
这个是不是
Xiaoning's
就不算小涂的
personal KPI?
个人业绩了
You don't have to worry about me.
这个没关系
It's my duty to help you.
也是我应该做的
Mr. Liu.
柳总
I just came up and saw
我刚刚上来的时候
the large
看到下面
exhibition hall.
场馆那么大
[I thought they were lessees doing marketing.]
以为是租户自己在营销
[But you said it's a fair]
您刚才说是展销
and you have your own brand?
也是有我们自己的牌子
Exactly.
那太有了
[You haven't sorted it out yet.]
你俩没搞清关系啊
[We are the supplier,]
我们是供应商
they are
那些都是
channel agents.
各级代理
They have to buy from us.
他们得从我们这儿进货
May I ask
那不知道
how many days the fair will last
方不方便问一下
and what is
咱们这一场活动
the turnover per day
一般要办几天啊
for a fair
这一天的营业额
like this?
大概是多少
This is an
我们这个是以
industry summit.
行业峰会的形式
[It's all large quantity purchase orders.]
签的呢也都是大额订单
[It could be 30-40 million yuan]
这星城办一天下来
[a day.]
三四千万吧
More than that.
保守了
What are your
那我们收银方面
cashiering options?
是怎么操作的呢
[Cash.]
现金
[Cards.]
刷卡
[Alipay.]
支付宝
By all means.
反正给钱就行
I have an idea
我有个想法
I'd like to share.
想跟二位说说
Yes?
你说
How about working with our bank
不知您二位有没有想过
to achieve your
把促销活动
promotional goals?
跟我们银行合作
You can combine the promotional discount
就是把本来促销的折扣
with our bank card.
跟银行卡绑定
Discounts will be offered to
只要结算的时候
customers
拿的是
who pay with our bank's
我们银行的信用卡
credit or
或者是
debit card
借记卡
depending on
达到一定额度
the amount spent.
就可以折扣多少
So,
那
what good would that do us?
对我们有什么好处
Yeah.
对啊
Let me describe it from another aspect.
其实咱们可以这么理解
In this exhibition,
咱们所有活动里面
any money
刷卡的钱
settled with Dairui's card
都进入到我们
will go into the
在代瑞开办的
enterprise clearing account.
企业结算账户里面
When the deposit
只要满足了
accumulates to five million yuan,
五百万的存款
we'll offer the interest
我就可以给到你们二位
in excess of
超过
demand deposits.
活期存款的利息
For each increment of five million,
每递增五百万
rate points can be added.
就可以再增加利率点
You see,
你想
it's the same money.
同样是钱
If you put it in another bank,
我们放在其他银行
you'd only get a demand deposit interest.
只是一个活期的存款
But if you put it at Dairui,
但如果放在我们代瑞
you can have a very
就可以有一个
substantial incremental interest rate.
非常可观地递增利息
What do you say?
您二位看怎么样
[Sounds good to me.]
听起来不错
It's worth a try.
倒可以试试啊
Bro,
哥
what do you think?
你觉得怎么样
I think it's safer.
我觉得这个比较稳妥呀
[If this is the case,]
那既然这样你
tell me more about
你再把刚才那个
the loan program you just said.
贷款方案说一说
Maybe I'll give it a go.
没准我也觉得稳妥呢
Sure.
当然没问题了
I didn't expect
还真是没想到
you'd become so good
一个多月的工夫
in a month.
就变得这么厉害了
I thought
我还以为
you'd be discouraged
他们一开始拒绝贷款
when they
你会
refused your offer in the first place.
灰心难过呢
Because you taught me well.
主要还是纪总教得好
Marketing
营销
and negotiation cannot be rushed.
和谈判不能急于求成
We need to gather information
要在跟客户交谈中
from talking to our clients,
吸取有用的信息
then work on it.
徐徐图之
Seriously,
不过说真的啊
that was a very clever proposal
刚刚那个刷卡方案
you just made.
提得很巧妙
If this kind of
如果是这种大额订购
large quantity ordering can work
一旦跟我们银行
with our bank,
建立起来合作关系
the average daily settlements
就能带来难以预计的
would be beyond our estimate.
日均结算量
[Also, that cardholder discount]
另外那个持卡折扣
[is ingenious.]
我觉得也很巧妙
This will
这样可以
help us
帮助我们
get some more cards issued.
增加一些发卡量
It's also an advertisement
还可以给我们代瑞
for Dairui.
打了一波广告
Many birds with one stone.
一举多得
I guess it won't be long
我想用不了多久
before I have to
我就得
work for you.
跟着涂经理打工了
But the final
那还不是
decision is yours.
要等纪总拍板啊
Whether it's 5 million yuan
什么五百万额度
or incremental interest.
递增利息的
You're the boss.
我可做不了主
But thanks anyway.
不过还是要说一声谢谢
What for?
谢我什么呀
Thank you for understanding
当然是要谢谢你
me so well.
这么懂我了
In fact, I know
其实我知道
you're
你呢
capable
是有能力
and sure of
也有把握
making this work.
能够拿下来这单合作的
[But you keep finding excuses for me]
但是你一直找借口
to get involved.
让我来参与
I know you want me to
我知道你是希望我能够
get out of the shadows
赶快走出来
and back to normal life.
回归到正常的生活
Actually, I've had
其实歇也歇够了
enough rest.
玩也玩够了
I'm sure my mom
我相信我妈应该也希望
would have wanted me
我能够好好生活
to live and work well.
好好工作
So it's time
所以是时候
to move on.
向前看了
You worked so late yesterday.
昨天都忙到那么晚了
Do you want to take a break?
要不要休息一会儿啊
Honestly,
说实话
last night
昨天晚上的时候
I was on the edge.
我这根弦还紧绷着呢
I feel much more relaxed now.
现在感觉放松了很多了
It's over half an hour away.
还有半个多小时的路程
You can take a nap.
先睡会儿吧
Okay.
好
What a coincidence, Mr. Zhao.
赵经理这么巧啊
You are here to...
你也打
Xiaoning.
小涂
Fanggang.
小赵哥
Mr. Ji is back.
领导回来了
Why do you have his case?
他的包怎么在你这儿啊
We met at the elevator.
电梯遇到了
He went upstairs for the bank president.
领导上去找行长
So he let me bring the case here.
就把包给我让我带回来
When I came along with him,
平时我跟他一起回来
and he went to the president,
他直接去行长室
I offered to bring his case
我说把包拿给我
back here,
帮他带回来
and he never gave me,
他都不给我
like I'm an outsider.
搞得特别见外
You seem to be an insider.
跟你还挺不见外的
It's just...
顺路
no big deal at all.
顺路的事吗
Maybe
可能领导
he's in a good mood today.
他今天高兴吧
It's common.
这也正常吧
Maybe
说不定
he's busier than usual.
纪总今天就是有事呢
No.
不对
Don't you realize
你们难道没发现
he has a little bit of...
领导其实有一点这个
clean fetish on personal things?
私人物品洁癖吗
[He never let]
他的办公室
[anyone in to clean]
从来没有让任何人进去
[his office.]
打扫过和收拾过
Well.
不是
You've seemingly finished your KPI
我说你们这个月
for the month, aren't you?
业绩都完成了是吗
You don't have better things to do?
这么闲吗
You want to
就因为领导
talk about who takes
一个包的问题
Mr. Ji's case
是谁拿进来
all day long?
就在这儿讨论半天
And you.
还有你
You're a senior.
也作为一个领导
Don't do naive things
跟着瞎掺和
like this.
真不应该啊
Yeah, I don't have better
是挺闲的
things to do.
要不
I only do things
怎么会做出一些
lacking of consideration
不过脑子
and annoying.
讨人嫌的事呢
Xiaoning, since you are here,
小涂你出来得正好
I have something about a client to ask.
我有个客户的事跟你说
Come with me.
你跟我来一趟
Okay.
好
You went to see a client this afternoon?
下午去跑客户啦
How's it going?
还顺利吗
They actually need a loan,
他们其实是需要贷款
but it has to be better value.
只是需要性价比更高的
They want a cooperation on the exhibition.
展销活动给我们做
When we
到时候
go there and
我们去办理
open service,
结算卡的时候
we can also
顺道
promote our credit cards.
营销一波信用卡
If you're successful
那如果这个项目
in this project,
你要是顺利拿下的话
you're one step closer to becoming
你的转正第二大关
a permanent employee.
也就闯过了
Congratulations.
提前恭喜你啊
Well,
别
don't congratulate me now.
姐你别提前恭喜我
Let's wait
还是等手续
until it's done.
都过完了以后再说吧
I'm still scared about
杨总的事我现在想想
what happened to Mr. Yang.
还有点后怕
Xiaoning.
筱柠
You're working pretty well
你现在这个工作状态呢
right now.
挺好的
Why?
怎么说呀
A woman should never
女人呢
give up her career
永远不要为了感情
for a relationship
放弃自己的事业
especially don't
更不要为了男人
give up job
还有爱情
for men and romance.
放弃自己的工作
So, no matter what happens,
这样不管发生什么
you'll be able to walk away
你都有全身而退的底气
and live alone.
一个人也可以过得很好
Jing.
静姐
Mr. Ji an I...
我跟纪总
You don't have to tell me.
你不用跟我说
I'm not interested in
你跟他的事
what you're doing with him.
我也不感兴趣
I just want to remind you that
我只是想提醒你的是
since you have chosen him,
既然你选择了他
you have to be prepared
你就要做好
for you to resign once
你们关系被曝光之后
your relationship comes into public.
随时走的可能性
Don't worry.
姐你放心
I'll try my best
我一定会努力
to keep myself here.
我不会走的
He and I
我们俩
have set the KPIs.
定了关键绩效指标
Whoever doesn't qualify them leaves.
谁没完成谁走
A bet, huh?
对赌啊
Ji Yuheng is a fair man.
纪昱恒这个人还挺公道
I'd like to ask
那我想问一下现在
who has the upper hand,
关键绩效指标
based on the current KPIs?
谁占上风啊
Being a permanent employee
转正以后呢
will be half way to my goal
我的关键绩效指标
of KPI.
就算完成了一半了
As for his,
至于他的
I don't know much.
我不太清楚
He's very careful not to
这方面他可精了
reveal anything.
捂得特别严实
I wish you success
那我就只能
in advance.
提前祝你成功
Thanks.
好
No.
不对
You must be the winner.
是必须成功
You're my pupil.
你是我饶静的徒弟
Even if you're up against
即使你的对手是
the current leader of Section 1 of BDD,
现在拓展一部的领导
you have to win.
也不行
Come on.
来吧
Cheer up!
加油
Sir.
老师
Yuheng.
昱恒
Here.
来 来 来
Have a seat.
坐 坐 坐
I thought you were
我还以为
taking a few more days off.
你要多休息几天呢
I'm pretty well rested.
调整得也差不多了
So I decided
就想着
to get back to work.
也得赶紧回来工作
So what's your plan for the future?
那接下来有什么打算吗
After all, you agreed to
毕竟你之前
come here
答应到我这儿来
because of your mother.
也是为了你母亲
Don't worry, sir.
老师您可以放心
You told me you wanted
之前您跟我说
me to bring Section 1 of BDD
要让拓展一部
back to life.
起死回生
I'll keep
这个约定
my promise.
我一定会替您完成
I also would like
另外我也希望
my teammates
我团队里跟着我的人
to have more opportunities.
能够有机会更进一步
More opportunities?
展开说说
Recently, the government
最近政府啊
has a deposit-only program.
有一个纯存款的项目
If we're able
如果我们能够
to take it,
顺利拿下来
maybe we'll
兴许之前
get a result for our
跟您立的军令状
previous appointment.
就能有一个结果了
And?
还有呢
You're a man
你这个走一步
who always think further.
想十步的人
There must be more
应该
you have known.
不止于此吧
You know me better than I do.
还是老师您了解我
I've heard about
我听说
a new opportunity
最近行里
in Dairui lately.
有一个新的机会
So I thought I'd come by
所以想着今天过来
and try to get it.
试着争取一下
We've all read
招标文件
the bidding documents.
大家看得都差不多了
I'll sum it up.
我总结一下
It's a government
这是一个政府的
deposit-only program.
纯存款项目
There are a dozen banks
参与竞标的
that participated in the bidding process.
一共有十几家银行
Two banks will be selected
最终会根据利率
based on their interest rates.
选出两家银行竞标成功
Compared to the targeted deposit
相对国有银行
products of state-owned banks,
有针对性的存款产品呢
ours are simple
我们的产品比较单一
[and less competitive.]
不太具有优势
I don't think so.
我倒是不这么觉得
Dairui
我们代瑞
has a lot of experience
之前对金额较大的竞标
with larger bids before.
还是很有经验的
If I remember correctly,
我记得没错的话
Ms. Rao,
饶经理
you've done some of those projects.
你也亲自操过刀吧
Yeah, so?
有啊怎么了
Mr. Ji.
纪总
Can you give me
能不能
this task?
把这个任务交给我
I can do this.
我有信心完成
This is, after all,
这毕竟是一个
government-related.
政府方向的任务嘛
Better count on
还是交给
Ms. Rao and Mr. Zhao
饶经理跟赵经理
who
会
are more experienced.
更有经验一些
The rest of us are also part of the effort
我们其他人共同努力
and will get fair share of it.
合理分配业绩
I'm okay with it.
我没有问题
Right.
行
Then let's do our best.
那大家就一起努力
Ms. Rao.
饶经理
You're better
竞标这一块
at bidding.
你比较擅长
You take care
标书
of the bid document.
就你来负责呗
Okay.
可以啊
Then I'll leave
那其他的辅助性
the rest of works
统筹工作
to you.
就有劳赵经理了
Fine by me.
没问题啊
Can I help Jing
我可以帮
write the bid?
静姐写投标书吗
I want to learn.
我想学习一下
Okay.
当然
I can work on the data.
数据这一块可以交给我
I'm good at it.
扒数字我擅长
It's my forte.
强项
Good.
好啊
Then Tang will work with Xu Li
那小唐就跟着许力一起
on the data.
负责数据方面的任务
What about me?
那我
A cheer leader?
不能只做啦啦队吧
How about this?
这样
I'll prepare bidder's information
我带着大小姚
for the bid with Yaos.
我们做那个竞标资料
Alright.
没问题
Sir.
领导
Consider it done.
放心
Just prepare yourself
你就等着
to sign the contract.
签合同吧
We work as one.
大家齐心协力
We can do this.
加油
We're right in front.
我们就在门口了呀
No results yet?
还没出结果
How come you
不是你怎么
don't have any inside info?
一点内部消息都没有啊
Mr. Ji.
纪总
We're going to work harder.
以后咱们再接再厉
What do you mean?
啥意思
A hundred million?
一个亿
Eight hundred million?
八个亿
We did it!
成了 成了 成了
We did it.
成了
A deposit of 8 hundred million.
八个亿的纯存款
It's a tough battle.
太不容易了
[You're the soul of Section 1]
你就是我们拓展一部的
[of BDD.]
团魂啊
It's all your credit.
都是你的功劳
Don't let me take the credit.
这次我是乐享其成
You're the ones who made it.
功劳都是你们大家的
Fanggang!
赵哥 赵哥
Hit me!
打我 打我 打我
Stop.
行
[Mr. Ji, Fanggang.]
领导 赵哥
[We've been working]
咱们这段时间
[too hard.]
熬成狗一样
[I didn't expect]
但我真没想到
[we'd be able to do it.]
咱真能接下来
[It's 8 hundred million!]
八个亿太多了
[Yeah.]
对啊
[It'll not only fulfill]
八个亿新增
this quarter's target,
别说咱们这个季度了
but even this year's.
这一年咱们的业绩
We're blessed.
都站稳了
Xiaoning.
小涂
With a record like this, you're
有这么突出的业绩
definitely being a permanent employee!
你还怕代瑞不让你转正
Yeah!
说得对
[If the bank]
要是
[doesn't think]
咱们行还是觉得
[it's enough,]
存款不够的话
you can take
我把我
my performance
那几个亿
as yours.
都存在你个人名下
But don't forget to return the favor.
回头记得还我啊
She can do it herself
人家小涂不需要你帮
without your help.
自己也能转正
Right?
是吧
[Okay.]
行
Listen.
这样
Today,
今儿啊
I'll make an exception
小赵哥破费一次
to treat you all to dinner.
请大家
An extortionate one!
吃大餐
[Let's go!]
出发
[Be my guest!]
那得多吃一点
I got my interview invitation.
我收到转正面试通知了
Really?
真的
You can do this.
加油
Victory is in sight.
最后一步了
I know.
知道了
See you.
走啦
Congratulations!
恭喜你啊
Check out the fireworks
快看我们拓展一部
we prepared for you.
为你准备的烟花
Thank you.
谢谢
Thank you all.
谢谢各位同事
Okay.
行了
You're done congratulating.
都恭喜完了
Go back
散了吧
to your work.
该干吗干吗
Alright, alright.
行 行 行
Thanks, Fanggang.
谢谢小赵哥
Xiaoning.
小涂
I'll buy you
小赵哥
dinner.
请你吃饭
Thank you.
好
Congratulations.
恭喜
Why don't you tell your family?
还不快点通知家人
Xiaoning.
筱柠
You've got
你现在
a great family
家庭美满
and a great career now.
事业有成
Keep going!
继续保持
Tell them.
快点
[I passed the interview.]
我通过面试了
[I'm a permanent employee now!]
我转正了
[I used to stand at]
曾经站在
[the crossroads of my 27th year]
二十七岁的分叉路口
[trying to hold on to]
想要用力抓住的
[some sense of security.]
那些安全感
[Now I have made it.]
如今都已经握在手里了
[Tu Xiaoning.]
涂筱柠
[You're probably]
此刻的你
[the happiest person]
大概是世界上
[in the world right now.]
最幸福的人了吧
Finance manager of Shunjue?
舜决的财务经理
Uncle,
李叔
thank you for telling me.
谢谢您的看重
But
但是
I'm not thinking of
我还没有
leaving Dairui yet.
从代瑞离职的想法
I know it's a rare opportunity.
我知道机会难得
I'll think about it.
我会考虑的
Thank you, Mr. Li.
谢谢李叔
[Do it yourself.]
你自己改
Good news.
好消息
My fellow brothers
家人们
and sisters.
战友们
It's finally our turn
这泼天的富贵
to enjoy the fortune.
终于轮到我们了
Li Xiang.
李想
A round of applause.
给点掌声呗
I,
我
your dearest Fanggang,
你们的小赵哥
has been shortlisted for
由于 个人能力突出
the business cadre
业绩优良
competition this round
入围了行里
due to my
新一轮的
outstanding competence!
业务骨干竞聘
More applause, Li Xiang!
能不能开心一点李想
Hurray!
好 好 好
[Congratulations!]
恭喜赵哥
[Thank you.]
谢谢
You know
你们也知道
the non-performing loan thing.
我之前那笔不良贷款
The superiors were thinking
上面一直觉得
I was unreliable.
我这个人不靠谱
This time
这次
I've made
也算是
a clean break.
一雪前耻了
Not only this time,
别说这次了
Mr. Zhao.
赵经理
The last time we secured a deal
就上次咱们那
of 8 hundred million.
八个亿的事
We couldn't have made it
如果没有咱们赵经理
without you.
八块钱都拉不来
Applaud!
掌声
You're making me flush.
话也不能这么说
It's a credit
那饶经理
to you, Ms. Rao,
跟在座的诸位
and everybody here
也是付出了
too.
很多心血的吗
This applause
这个掌声
is for everyone!
是送给大家的
I'm not done yet.
话还没说完啊
All of you have made
这次政府存款
outstanding contributions to
大家
this government deposit program.
都有卓越的贡献
Li Xiang,
李想
you can get a salary raise!
工资涨一级
Really?
真的
[I can get a raise?]
我还能涨一级
Xu Li.
许力
Congrats.
恭喜你
You're now
你的职级
an account manager
调到了客户经理的
of the highest rank!
最高档
Next step,
下一步
you'll be in line
就能入围
for Senior Account Manager.
高级客户经理的行列了
Seriously?
真的假的
[I never thought]
高级客户经理
[I'd go for Senior Manager.]
我就不想了
[I thought getting to Tier 3]
但调职级到三级
[would take me]
我以为
[at least another]
我怎么得
2 or 3 more years.
再熬个两三年呢
The boss already
人家领导都去
signed off at HR.
人力资源部给你签字了
It's the real deal!
还能有假
Our leader deserves a statue!
领导配享太庙
A statue? You should be crying!
享什么太庙你得哭
No way, I'm not crying!
我不哭
Fanggang,
小赵哥
what about Jing?
我们静姐呢
Ms. Rao
饶经理
got promoted
升职了
to Chief Account Manager,
举世罕见的
a rare honor!
首席客户经理
Congratulations, Jing!
恭喜静姐
Congrats, Ms. Rao!
恭喜饶经理
I heard
我听说这次
they sent
一共送去总部
ten candidates to HQ,
十个候选人
even before the
而且还是在政府项目
[government project was secured.]
拿到之前就提报上去了
[Could it be that Mr. Ji]
不会是纪总
[had this planned?]
提前都计划好了吧
[Don't you think?]
你别说啊
The boss is really sharp
领导真的太厉害了
how did he
你说他怎么
even predict this?
算出来的呢
Maybe it wasn't about predicting.
那也许不是算出来的呢
He believes in us
是领导相信我们
and in Jing.
相信静姐
Group photo
为纪念拓展一部
by the front sign
连续两个季度
to commemorate
业绩排名第一
S1's
大家
two straight quarters
一起去门口的牌子前
of top rankings!
合照去
Let's go!
走
Let's go.
走 走 走
Today is just too exciting.
今天很开心
See you in a bit!
一会儿见啊
See you!
一会儿见
If you want to say thank you,
想说感谢的话
just say it.
就大大方方地说
You're a force
那谈业务的时候
to be reckoned with
大杀四方
in business,
雷霆万钧
but
怎么
when it comes to relationship,
一到感情
it's like your words burn your tongue.
这话就跟烫嘴似的
Mr. Zhao,
不是赵经理
are you speaking for me now?
你是我嘴替啊
When did I say
我什么时候想说
I wanted to thank someone?
感谢的话了
You didn't say it,
虽然你嘴上不说
but your face gave you away.
但你表情出卖了你
I...
我
Yep,
就是这么
that little glance down and the pout
一垂眼一努嘴
it says it all.
就是这意思
Mr. Zhao,
不是赵经理
do you have some special hobby?
你没有什么特殊癖好吧
Why are you always watching me?
没事老观察我干什么
Got a spying fetish or something?
有偷窥癖啊你
What if I've got
看上你
a crush on you?
算吗
Xiaoning,
小涂
why are you standing so far to the side?
你怎么站这么靠边啊
Move over here.
你站这边
It'll look better in the photo.
这样画面好看
Look at the camera. Come on.
来看镜头 来
Ms. Tu,
涂经理
smile naturally!
笑得自然点
With such a handsome guy like Mr. Ji
纪总这么大的帅哥
next to you,
在你旁边
you should be beaming!
你应该乐开花才对啊
Stop joking around
别开玩笑了
and just take the picture.
赶紧拍
All right, hold it.
来就这样
In
来
3,
三
2,
二
1...
一
Okay, listen up.
来 我说一下
Go home and pack your things,
大家回去收拾一下东西
and you can start
明天就可以过来
officially tomorrow.
正式上班了
Got it, see you tomorrow.
好嘞 明天见
Qi Yu.
齐郁
Uh... My girlfriend's here.
那个我女朋友来了
See you tomorrow.
咱明天见
All right, see you tomorrow.
行那明天见
Congrats!
恭喜你啊
Here,
拿着
I took leave just to be here.
我专门请假过来的
I knew I had to witness you
我就想着一定要见证
becoming a police officer.
你成为警察的这一刻
I know how hard
这一路走来
you've worked to get here,
我知道你有多么不容易
and I'm so proud of you.
我真心地为你感到骄傲
We might not see each other
就是咱们两个以后
as much at work anymore,
不能经常在公司见面了
but don't worry,
不过你放心
I'll do my best
我会在新单位
at the new place
好好努力地
and honor the police badge.
不会辜负警察这份荣誉
Yes, sir.
好的齐警官
I prepared
今天知道你入职
a little something
给你准备了一份
to celebrate your new job.
小小的入职礼物
I thought this is the gift.
这不是有礼物吗
There's more.
还有
I can do it on my own.
我自己来就行
Starting tomorrow,
明天起啊
you'll be in uniform,
你就要开始穿制服了
and if you want to stand out,
行头上想要出挑呢
you've got to start with your shoes.
就得从鞋上下文章
Weiyi, actually,
惟依
the unit provides us with shoes.
其实我们单位发皮鞋了
You don't have to do this.
不用这么折腾
It's fine.
一点都不折腾
My dad's a regular here.
我爸呀是这家店的常客
The shoes here
你看他这鞋
are not only comfortable
不但穿着很舒服
but also have a low-key style
而且样式也挺低调的
that people who know will appreciate.
懂的人一看就懂
[We just got in]
今天店里
[two pieces of crocodile leather today,]
新到了两张鳄鱼皮
[enough to make a pair]
刚好够做一双
[in this gentleman's size.]
这位先生的尺码
Crocodile leather?
鳄鱼皮
No, no,
算了吧
that's too much.
什么鳄鱼皮
Would you prefer calfskin?
那你喜欢小牛皮
French
要法产的
or Italian?
还是意大利产的
Weiyi,
惟依
I actually...
我其实想
I remember you told me
我记得你好像跟我说过
your uniform is dark,
你们制服是深色的
so let's go with the French leather
那就法产的吧
and a
然后来一个
subtle gradient brown.
低调一点的渐变棕
[No problem,]
好的 没问题
[it'll be ready in two weeks.]
半个月后您来取货
[You can pay the deposit over here.]
这边付一下定金
Sure.
行
Weiyi...
惟依
I know what you're going to say.
我知道你要说什么
Qi Yu,
齐郁
becoming a police officer
你现在是当上警察了
is a huge
这可是你
milestone in your life,
人生当中的大事
and I have to give you
我必须要送给你个
a fitting gift.
像样点的礼物
If you keep protesting,
你要是再这样
I'll be upset.
我可要不开心了
That's a yes, right?
那我就当你答应了
Yes!
耶
Time to clock out!
到点下班了
Today's the first day of my raise,
今天是我加薪的第一天
so I'm treating myself.
我准备自己去消费一下
What about you guys?
各位呢
I'm planning to have
我准备今天
a big meal
大吃一顿
and really spoil myself.
然后好好犒劳犒劳自己
I have to attend
我爸有个晚宴
a dinner party with my dad.
我要去参加一下
A dinner party?
晚宴
Yuhui,
小唐
um...
那个
can I tag along
能不能
and see how the big shots live?
带师父去长长眼
My crowd is full of VIPs.
我那都是有头有脸的人
Xiaoning,
小涂
there's a new BBQ place.
那边新开了一家烤肉店
Want to check it out with me?
姐带你过去尝尝啊
Sorry, my parents
姐我爸妈做好饭
are expecting me
在家等我了
for dinner at home.
不好意思啊
Maybe
下次呗
next time, though?
下次你带我去
No worries.
没关系
I've got other plans anyway.
反正我也约了别人
[We'll go next time.]
下次有机会的啊
Jing,
静姐
let me guess
我们盲猜一下
you're hitting up a bar tonight,
你晚上肯定得去酒吧
having some drinks,
喝酒
and dancing with some handsome guys.
然后找帅哥跳舞
Is that even a guess?
不是这还用盲猜吗
It's basically my signature move.
这不姐保留节目吗
Right, Fanggang,
对了赵哥
any plans tonight?
今天晚上什么安排
Want to
要不要
grab dinner with me?
跟我一块吃饭啊
No plans.
没安排
I'm saving
一块钱
every penny for my projects,
都能指着下崽生孩的人
trying to make
得留下来继续搞钱
some money.
搞项目
Fanggang,
小赵哥
are you talking about
你说的项目是不是
the bike project?
自行车那个呀
I've discussed it with Jing before.
我之前跟静姐有所了解
Need a hand?
要不我帮帮你呗
No need, Xiaoning,
不用了小涂
but thanks.
谢谢啊
I wouldn't want
这些小事
to trouble our
就不劳烦
Chief Account Manager with small stuff.
首席客户经理了
I'm heading out.
我先走了
Bye.
拜拜
See you, Fanggang.
小赵哥拜拜
Bye, everyone.
拜拜 拜拜
All right,
来
let's go.
走吧
Everyone's got family, friends,
有爹有妈有家
and someone special.
有朋友有对象
How can they all be so lively?
他们怎么能这么热闹
You okay?
姐你还好吧
You seem down.
心情不好
I got promoted.
我升职了
Congrats!
那恭喜你啊
Thanks.
谢谢啊
But besides telling you,
但是除了分享给你
I don't know who else
我也不知道
to share it with.
还能分享给谁
I used to see you
之前总见你跟一些男生
with a bunch of guys here.
一块来这儿
[What happened?]
最近怎么啦
[You're always alone lately.]
你总是一个人
Really?
是吗
I didn't
你不说我好像
even notice.
都不知道
I'm fine, you go ahead.
我没事了你去忙吧
Sure.
好
Let's see...
让我来挑一个
Doesn't seem that exciting.
好像也没什么意思
Happy promotion to me.
升职快乐
My daughter has worked so hard for this.
我女儿太不容易了
[Finally, she's made it.]
终于转正了
[She's officially an Account Manager now.]
当上客户经理了
It's just a promotion,
我就转个正
why are you both so excited?
你们俩激动成这样
How did her important photo
她这这么重要的照片
turn out so bad?
怎么拍这么难看啊
Yuheng,
小纪啊
can this photo be retaken?
这照片能重拍一下吗
I think it looks great.
挺好看的
Stop it.
你别捣乱了
No matter what, she's your daughter.
你再丑也是你生的
My daughter is beautiful,
我女儿可美了
just didn't wear makeup.
就是没化妆
Yours isn't so great either.
你女儿才丑呢
What's going on with you two?
你们俩咋回事啊
I just got promoted,
我好不容易转正
and instead of praising me,
不夸夸我
you're criticizing my photo.
还说我照片拍得丑
[Is it really that bad? Let me see.]
丑吗我看看
Is it?
丑吗
It's not bad at all.
一点都不丑
Makeup or no makeup,
不管化不化妆
you're the most beautiful
你在我心里
in my eyes.
都是最好看的
See,
你学学
learn from our son-in-law.
你看俺女婿这情商
Dad, all thanks to you.
爸教得好
My wife's the most beautiful ever,
我老婆是天底下最美的
and so is my daughter.
我女儿也美
Both are beautiful.
都美
Now that's more like it.
这还差不多
Listen,
说好了啊
every time I get a promotion or a raise,
以后只要我升职加薪
we'll have a big feast,
我们就吃一顿大餐
on me.
我请客
Fine,
行
but next time you get promoted,
那记得下次升职
make sure the photo turns out better.
把照片拍好看点啊
Xiaoning,
筱柠啊
dad wishes you continued success.
爸爸祝你步步高升啊
Within 10 years,
十年之内
you'll be a bank president.
咱弄个行长当当
A bank president?
行长
President Tu.
涂行长
Or President Ji.
纪行长
Now that your promotion is settled,
这转正也尘埃落定了
what's your plan?
接下来有什么打算
I plan to
我打算
take a slow
跟纪总
walk home with Ji.
慢慢地走回家
I overate earlier.
刚才吃东西太多了
I meant
我问的是
your work plan.
你工作上的打算
What,
怎么
are you
你要打探
trying to dig into
我关键绩效指标的进度
my KPI progress?
是不是啊
No comment.
无可奉告
Speaking of progress,
说到进度
doesn't every bit of yours
你的哪一笔进度
pass through me anyway?
不都得过我的手
No need to dig.
我还需要专门打听吗
True enough.
倒也是啊
My short-term goal
短期目标呢
is to attend tomorrow's
就是明天去
glass product launch
装潢玻璃的新品发布会
and do some serious marketing.
多多营销
Mid-term,
中期目标呢
I'll hit
就是完成咱们俩
our KPI
对赌协议里的
from the bet,
关键绩效指标
securing 50 million in savings.
拉到五千万的存款
But with
那刚刚拉到的
the 800 million in government deposits
政府的八亿的存款
we just secured,
分到你头上
doesn't that already
那五千万
cover your 50 million?
不就已经达到了吗
I don't want that.
我才不要呢
I've got pride.
我可是很有骨气的
I want to earn that deposit
我要靠自己的本事
on my own merit.
拉到存款
Otherwise, even if I win,
要不然我赢了
it wouldn't feel right.
也觉得胜之不武啊
Impressive.
不错嘛
What about long-term goals?
那长期目标呢
Long-term?
长期目标呢
Stick with S1
就是待在拓展一部
and work hard.
好好工作
You know
你都知道了
all about my progress,
我的进度条到哪儿了
so how about
你也跟我
you share yours with me?
分享分享你的呗
My progress?
我的进度条啊
I'm not so sure.
我也不清楚
Come on.
你怎么这样呀
You know everything about me,
你对我的了如指掌
and I know nothing about you.
我对你的是毫不知情
This isn't fair.
这太不公平了
Well, that's just how it is.
但是没办法
It's our
这是咱俩的
job roles.
职责属性所在
I'm Mr. Ji,
谁让我是纪总
and you're Xiaoning.
你是小涂呢
Fine,
那行
let me rephrase.
那我换一个问法
Now that
我现在转正了
I'm officially
也算是你的
your right-hand woman,
左膀右臂了
what's the
那请问纪总
next phase
下一个阶段的工作目标
of your work plan?
是什么呢
That's a fair question, right?
这样总可以吧
Speaking of opportunities,
说到机会啊
there's one right now.
现在确实有一个
You've heard of Weiji Group, right?
惟纪知道吧
Of course.
当然
They're the top leisure
就是全国休闲旅游
and tourism company nationwide,
排名第一的公司
with resorts
他们的度假村
in every
在一线城市
major city.
可以说遍地开花
This year, they're
今年呢
expanding into second-tier cities.
准备往二线发展了
I got a tip.
我还有个小道消息
They just acquired land
他们刚在城北
in the north of the city
拿了一块地
and are planning to move into Xing City.
正准备进军星城
So
那这么说
if they've just bought land,
刚刚拿了一块地
their funds will be tight.
那资金会收紧
If they plan to build a resort,
如果再建度假村的项目
they'll likely
十有八九
need financing.
会融资的
Seems like
看来你是
you've already
早就在
been eyeing this.
打这个主意了是吧
That's right.
没错
Think about it,
你想啊
since they're developing properties
他们既然要在星城
in Xing City,
这块地盘上开发
local banks like ours
那本地银行肯定就会
will have a chance to work with them.
有机会跟他们合作
Exactly.
是
I've already mentioned this
这件事呢
to Xing in S2,
我还跟二部的小邢说过
and he's very interested.
他很有意愿
If you're also keen,
如果你也有兴趣
that would be even better.
那就更好了
With both of you
你想这样咱们代瑞
working on it,
就可以双管齐下
our chances of winning are higher,
赢面又大
and it would significantly
对你下一个目标
help you with your next goal.
也会有很大的助益
As long as you support me,
只要老师支持
I'll give it my all.
我一定放开了去干
Speaking of the next phase,
其实说到下一个阶段
there's something
我还真的有一件事情
I need to discuss with you.
想跟你好好商量一下
I'm about
接下来我可能面临的
a rare opportunity
是我职业生涯里面
in my career,
非常难得一遇的机会
and I want to go for it.
我想要争取一下
What kind of opportunity?
什么机会啊
Competing for a branch president position.
竞聘行长
What?
怎么了
Is the current president stepping down,
行长不干了
or
还是
are you staging a coup?
你要起义
Neither, of course.
当然都不是了
The headquarters
其实总行
plans to set up
想要在星城新区
a new branch
筹备了一个
in Xing City's new district,
新的集安分行
and the president position
那里行长的位置
is still open.
还空着呢
You want to apply for it?
你想竞聘
Yes.
是
Positions like this
其实放眼
only open up
整个星城的银行界
every 4 or 5 years
像这种位置
in the Xing City
可能需要四五年
banking scene.
才会空出来一个
If I can
如果我真的可以
get it,
应聘上的话
it would be
就相当于是
a huge step forward.
上了一个大的台阶
Otherwise,
否则
I'll have to wait
只能在
in my current role
部门经理的位置上
for another 4 or 5 years
继续再等个四五年
for the next chance.
才有可能有下一次机会
It's different for you
在你们这个位置
at that level.
跟我们不一样
Getting promoted
你们想要升职
is tough.
真的是太难了
You have to wait
要等到有人
for a spot to open up
把位置空出来
before you can move up.
你们才能往上面走一步
With such
那现在有一个
a great opportunity,
这么好的机会
I'm sure
肯定很多人
many people are eyeing it.
虎视眈眈地呀
What's your plan?
你打算怎么做呀
Weiji Group is planning
惟纪集团要在星城
to develop a resort in Xing City,
开发一个度假村
and they'll need financing.
到时候需要融资
The project
但是这笔融资
is massive
体量很大
and complex.
难度也很高
If someone
如果说谁能够
can secure this deal,
把这个项目拿下来
they'll gain significant favor
一定可以在总行领导那
with headquarters,
得到重视
giving them more leverage.
也就有更多的主动权了
Weiji Group...
惟纪集团
I studied them once.
我学习的时候了解过它
Their CEO is Xia Mingrui,
他们总裁叫夏明睿
but I've heard
不过听说
he's very picky.
他是一个很挑剔的人
Securing this deal won't be easy.
拿下他肯定很不容易
But what's tough for others
别人不容易
is easy for you.
我们纪总就不一样啦
You can
他呢
achieve anything you set your mind to,
什么事情都能做到
and I'll support you
只要你想做
all the way.
我就支持你
Does this mean
那以后
I should start calling you
我是不是要改口了
President Ji?
叫你纪行长
That's one
其实刚刚说的那些
part of it,
是一个部分
but there's something more important.
还有更重要的一点
If I
如果说我
get this promotion,
真的能够竞选上
I can leave S1,
我就可以离开一部
and we
咱们俩
can be
就可以光明正大地
together openly,
在一起了
without hiding.
就不用提心吊胆了
That's a huge benefit!
有这么大的好处啊
All the more reasons to support you.
那我更要支持你了
But don't
不过还是希望
stress too much.
你别有那么大的压力
Don't worry.
放心
I'm working hard to grow quickly,
我会尽快地成长起来
to stand on my own.
独当一面
If it
有一天
ever comes to it,
就算我们被发现了
and one of us has to leave,
必须要走一个人
I hope
我也希望
I'm strong enough
我有这个底气
to land a job even better.
可以找到更好的去处
Xiaoning,
筱柠
if I succeed,
如果说我真的成功了
let's get married.
我们结婚吧
Ji Yuheng,
纪昱恒
you're something else.
你可真行啊
A proposal
画饼式求婚
with a side of wishful thinking?
我可真是第一次听说
Let's talk about it when you succeed.
等你成功了再说吧
Take the bag.
拿着
I have a full day of marketing tomorrow,
明天还要站一天营销呢
and my legs are already hurting.
我今天腿就开始疼了
Got it.
懂了
Let's go home.
回家
Come on,
来
I'll give you a piggyback.
背你回去
Thank you, Mr. Ji.
那就辛苦纪总啦
Let's go.
走了
Hold on tight.
坐好了啊
All set?
填好了是吗
Here.
给
Great.
好
This is
这个呢是
a complimentary
您办卡
digital scale as a little gift
送给您的一个体重秤
for opening an account.
就算是个小礼物
You can pick it up
您到我们银行
at any of our
任何一个网点
bank branches.
都可以领取
Best wishes for your new home.
祝您搬新家称心如意
A digital scale, huh?
电子秤啊
That's actually pretty useful.
这礼物挺实用的嘛
Thanks.
谢谢啊
Hello.
您好 您好
Just fill out this form,
先把这个表格填一下
and you're all set.
就可以了
Xiaoning.
小涂
Jing.
静姐
Today's marketing gifts
今天这个营销礼品
are on point.
选得不错啊
I figured
我就是想着
today's crowd would include
今天来的不只有经销商
both dealers and people
还有很多人来看玻璃
looking to renovate,
准备装修的
so
就
I chose
准备了一些
some practical
比较实用的
small appliances.
小家电
It's all thanks to your guidance.
还是师父教得好
With your
你这个
practical thinking,
因地制宜的思维吧
I'd say
我看
Ji Yuheng might actually
纪昱恒确实有
have some competition.
被挤走的可能啊
Really?
是吗
[Geng Nianyi is here!]
耿念一来了
[Geng Nianyi!]
耿念一哎
Jing.
姐
is that her?
她就是耿念一
She hasn't done
她好像很久
events in a long time.
没有出来做活动了
[She's a nationally renowned host,]
全国知名主持人
but has stayed low-key since marriage.
就是婚后很少出来了
It took
这回
a lot to get her
费了好大的劲
here today.
才把她给找来
Hello, everyone,
大家好
I'm Geng Nianyi.
我是耿念一
Welcome to the
欢迎大家来到
Wutong Glass New Product Launch.
梧桐玻璃的新品发布会
Wutong Glass
梧桐玻璃的品牌
is a well-known brand that has been
是我们畅销了业内
leading the decoration industry
十几年的一款
for over a decade,
中国驰名品牌
consistently holding
它一直以来
the top spot
也是我们业内的
as the industry leader.
装潢品牌的头号领导者
Mr. Liu,
柳总
why did they choose
他们怎么想到
to get Geng Nianyi to come?
把耿念一请过来的呀
She's got strong business skills,
业务能力强啊
a great reputation,
风评又好
and high popularity.
人气又高
In the era of social media,
你说这自媒体时代
finding someone this well-rounded
能找这么一个全面的人
isn't easy.
不容易啊
Look,
你看
[look at the live stream numbers]
你看这直播间人数
[they're skyrocketing.]
噌噌往上涨
[People are swarming in.]
你看这人气
She's beautiful,
人长得漂亮
talented,
业务能力也强
yet married?
怎么就结婚了
Mr. Liu,
柳总
who did she end up with?
她最后嫁给谁了
Rumor has it
据说啊
she married into
是嫁给一个
a mysterious, prominent family,
神秘的高门大户
which led her to step back.
要不然也不能隐退
But who she married
但具体是嫁给谁
is still a mystery.
是个谜
She really is stunning.
确实好看
We've been waiting here
咱在这儿啊
for four hours.
杵了四个小时了
If nothing goes wrong, meeting with
不出意外
Mr. Xia is about to go wrong.
见夏总的事要出意外了
Secretary Liu,
刘秘书你好
is Mr. Xia available now?
夏总现在时间方便吗
Sorry, Mr. Ji,
抱歉纪总
the last meeting
夏总上一个会议
ran a bit over,
时间开得稍微久了一点
and Mr. Xia had to
现在紧急前往
rush to the next one.
下一场会议了
He won't
今天
have time to see you today.
恐怕抽不出时间来见你
I understand.
理解
Can we
那明天的时间
schedule for tomorrow?
我们可以约吗
I'm afraid not, Mr. Ji.
不好意思纪总
Mr. Xia's schedule is fully booked
夏总最近一周的时间
for the next week.
都约满了
[You might have to wait a bit longer.]
您可能得再等一等
All right,
行
thanks.
那麻烦你了
Should we come up with a plan?
咱是不是得想想办法呀
At this rate,
看这形势
Mr. Xia will probably
一周后这夏总
still be busy next week.
十有八九也没空
In an hour,
一个小时以后
he will be at his private squash court
夏总会在城北的
in the north of the city.
私人壁球馆打球
Private squash court,
私人壁球馆
members-only,
会员制
owned by someone named Xu.
老板姓许
Does that ring a bell?
有印象了吗
You've only been here six months,
你这刚来半年
and you remember my client
我这一年半前的客户
from a year and a half ago?
你都记得
This photo looks like
这张照片看着
the smile is a bit forced.
笑得很不自然
Not at all.
不会啊
No matter how you smile,
你不管笑成什么样
I always think you look great.
我都觉得好看
[Class,]
同学们
[time's up.]
时间到了
[Please place your exams on the desk]
把卷子放在桌子上
[and exit in an orderly manner.]
有序离开吧